paper.li 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy

This Policy sets out our privacy practices and explains how we handle the information we collect when you visit and use our sites, services, products, and content ("Services").

**We value your privacy a lot. When you share information with us through the use of one of our Services, we make sure it is stored as securely as possible, and kept only for the purpose intended.**

As such, we never share the information you provide to third parties, except for chosen partners that are used for the purpose of providing you the best [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) experience.

You always remain in control of your data. You may edit or erase your data from our Services at any time.

When we refer to "we" or "us" in this policy, we mean [Finity SA](https://finity.ai/), which controls the information collected when you use the services (including but not limited to [Finity.ai](https://finity.ai/), [Paper.li](https://paper.li/), ...). This Policy does not apply to information collected by third-party Web sites linked to or otherwise accessible from [Paper.li](https://paper.li/). The information collected or received by third-party services is subject to their own privacy policies.

## How do we use the information we collect?

The information we collect is used solely for the purpose of operating and improving our Services.

When you visit one of our services, we collect usage information, log data and remarketing data.

We use usage information and log data to compute non-identifying reports that are used to improve our services. For that purpose, non-identifying usage information and log data are also shared with our third-party analytics services (including, but not limited to, Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics and HubSpot).

Log data may also be used to fight spam and other abuse of our services.

We use remarketing data to measure the conversion of marketing campaigns we sometimes do on external platforms like Facebook, Linkedin and Twitter, as well as present users who have visited our services relevant ads. Remarketing data is collected through the usage of tracking pixels. No personal information is contained in or collected as a result of using these tracking pixels.

Some [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) papers may include ads served by Google Ads. Google uses cookies to help serve personalized ads, as expressed within the Cookies section. More information can be found into [Google Advertising Privacy & Terms document](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

When you create an account on [Paper.li](https://paper.li/), you provide us account information.

From time to time, we use your email exclusively to send you information about new features of [Paper.li](https://paper.li/), best practices and [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) discounts. You can decide to opt out of these [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) marketing and product update communications at any time within your Paper.li account settings page under the Email notifications section.

We may also contact you to inform you about changes to our [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) Service and important Service-related notices, such as new Terms or other security notices. These communications are considered part of the Service and you may not opt out of them.

Your name and email address may be securely transmitted to our third parties (including, but not limited to, [customer.io](https://customer.io/)). We use those third-party tools as communication tools with you.

We also use your log data (more specifically your IP address) to know which country you are connecting from. This information is used for statistical purposes.

We also collect your usage information and log data as a visitor of one of our Services.

To benefit from our [Paper.li paid plan](https://paper.li/pro.html), you need to provide **billing information** and **payment details** (credit card or Paypal account). The **billing information** and **payment details** you provide when upgrading a paper are collected by our partner [Recurly](https://recurly.com/) and processed by our partner [Wirecard Bank AG](https://www.wirecardbank.com/GDPR). Recurly is PCI-DSS Level 1 compliant, a standard that provides a secure environment that goes above and beyond industry security standards and guidelines. Recurly privacy policy is available [under this page](https://recurly.com/legal/privacy). Wirecard Bank AG is one of the world’s leading independent providers of solutions for electronic payments and is a fully licensed German bank listed on the Frankfurt Securities Exchange.

Our partners **_never share with us payment details_** (that is, we never receive your credit card or Paypal account information under any circumstances).

Invoices and other billing information are sent by Recurly on our behalf to the billing information email address you have provided. You may edit your billing information and/or payment details at any time by clicking on the Billing Dashboard URL found in the Billing Info tab of your account settings.

We use [Zendesk.com](https://www.zendesk.com/) as a platform to handle assistance requests. Whenever you submit a [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) helpdesk ticket (either through email or the helpdesk request [online form](https://support.paper.li/hc/en-us/requests/new)), Zendesk collects on our behalf contact information which is used to communicate with you. Your communication and help requests are safeguarded and stored according to [Zendesk privacy policy](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/).

Your communication and help requests are stored indefinitely in Zendesk to document your support and billing requests with [Paper.li](https://paper.li/).

If you leave a comment on the [Paper.li blog](https://blog.paper.li/) or ask a question in one of our [Community Forums](https://support.paper.li/hc/en-us/community/topics), you should be aware that any information you provide to these websites - including profile information associated with the account you use to post the information - may be read, collected, and used by any member of the public who accesses those sites. Your profile and the information you enter may remain, even after you delete your account. To request removal of your information from these publicly accessible sites, please [contact us](https://support.paper.li/hc/en-us/requests/new).

When you share public content on social media (including but not limited to Twitter, Facebook, Youtube, Instagram), your public social media activity may end up in our platforms.

To understand more about the type of activity you share publicly, we encourage you to check the Terms and Privacy Policies of the social media networks you use.

From time to time, you may be mentioned on Twitter as a news sharer by our [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) service. You can turn off those mentions here.

If you do not want your content to be processed by our products at all, please reach out to us [here](https://support.paper.li/hc/en-us/requests/new).

## What information do we collect and store?

**Usage information** includes the pages you visit, your language preference, your location, device and Internet browser details, and so on.

**Log data** contain data about the nature of each access of our services, including originating Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, the requested files, operating system versions, device type and timestamps. Web servers usually keep log files that record data each time a device accesses those servers.

You might provide us with your **contact information** , whether through a form on our website, a subscription to a paper newsletter or an interaction with our customer support team. **Contact information** includes your email address and name.

To become a **Paper.li user** you need to have an account with us. At registration, you share with us your name and email address.

If you choose to register by using a third-party account (such as your Twitter or Facebook account), we receive your personal information (name, avatar, email, and so on) from third parties if you give permission to those third parties to share your information with us. **Your password for those third-party services is never shared with us.**

If you choose to register by email, you create a password (rest assured, your password is encrypted and stored securely).

All the aforementioned information (name, email address, password, personal information from third parties) constitutes your **account information**. In addition, your account information will also include any [Paper.li](https://paper.li/)-specific settings you add to your account.

To benefit from our [Paper.li paid plan](https://paper.li/pro.html), you need to provide **billing information** and **payment details** (credit card or Paypal account). The **billing information** and **payment details** you provide when upgrading a paper are collected by our partner [Recurly](https://recurly.com/) and processed by our partner [Wirecard Bank AG](https://www.wirecardbank.com/). Recurly is PCI-DSS Level 1 compliant, a standard that provides a secure environment that goes above and beyond industry security standards and guidelines. Recurly privacy policy is available [under this page](https://recurly.com/legal/privacy). Wirecard Bank AG is one of the world’s leading independent providers of solutions for electronic payments and is a fully licensed German bank listed on the Frankfurt Securities Exchange.

Our partners **_never share with us payment details_** (that is, we never receive your credit card or Paypal account information under any circumstances).

By **social media activity** we mean any activity that is publicly available on a social media network (including, but not limited to, Twitter, Facebook, Youtube, Instagram). Such activity usually contains your identifier, name (as entered by the social media), the content you shared, your current location, and so on.

The information we receive from social media networks is solely determined by each social media network, according to their privacy policy and terms of service. We encourage you to check their documentation to discover which kind of information they communicate with us.

## To whom do we transfer this information?

We do not share your information or data with third parties outside Finity except in the following limited circumstances (as highlighted under the section How do we use the information we collect?):

  * Track our service’s usage and provide reports to help us improve our services and conversions

  * Allow our customers to pay for our Services

  * Facilitate communication and marketing with you

  * Manage our customer support services to you.

We only select third parties with a strong commitment to privacy and security standards. When applicable, we enter into confidentiality and data processing agreements with them.

We will also share your information when we are obliged to do so under applicable laws or by order of the competent authorities.

## Data retention

All data explicitly shared with us remains under your control. At any time, you can decide to delete information you explicitly shared with us, and we will erase it completely from our Services.

Non-identifying information is set to expire after a given period of time. In some limited cases, some information must be kept indefinitely due to legal obligations.

The following sections describe our retention policy for each group of information.

Usage information shared with Google Analytics is kept up to 26 months after your last visit.

Log data stored on our platform is kept up to 6 months.

Log data shared with Google Analytics is kept up to 26 months after your last visit.

## How do we protect your personal information?

Finity and its authorized partners shall take appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect your [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) Information and traffic data provided to us/them or collected by us/them, and shall not retain it any longer than permitted in order to perform its Services or as required under relevant legislation. Your personal data can only be accessed by authorized employees of Finity, Finity authorized partners' employees needing to access this data to fulfill their given duties, or by [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) Pro Publishers in the case where you have a subscription to their online newspaper.

## Cookies

Like many websites, we use "cookie" technology to collect additional website usage data and to improve our Services. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer's hard disk. [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to better understand how you interact with our Services, to monitor aggregate usage by our users and web traffic routing on our services, and to customize and improve our Services.

We are also using 3rd party cookies. Examples of the services we may be using are:

  * Google Analytics ([Opt out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en))

  * Google Adwords & Adsense ([Opt out](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads?sig=ACi0TCiKv0pyMLJIr00kQGPkoOIrxs8juz-g714YMZ8MRIixOZSo3bRb8e4uLnYPtdJq-cmYv_7T-enp91qJxH5_r1DROECRFNlBntaQ8MVetM9b48EonzUWHNr2CaxFnK-Jfa4De6AjRUEE5oBkRXYh1j2L39DsPF0EY1eDEbqN2Pht0_BGrS0&hl=en))

  * Facebook ([Opt out](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217))

  * Criteo ([Deactivate](https://www.criteo.com/deactivate-criteo-banners/))

  * Addthis ([Learn more](https://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy#publisher-visitors))

  * Twitter ([Learn more](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170514-twitters-use-of-cookies-and-similar-technologies))

  * Linkedin ([Learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy))

You can also deactivate specific 3rd party cookies through the following page managed by the EDAA (European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance): [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. However, some Services may not function properly if you disable cookies.

You can visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for more information on how to manage and remove cookies across a number of different internet browsers.

## Can this Privacy Policy be modified?

Finity reserves the right to modify the provisions of this Privacy Policy if deemed necessary. We will inform you of these changes by publishing the revised Privacy Policy at [paper.li](https://paper.li/). The revised Privacy Policy shall become immediately effective once published. You agree that your continued use of the [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) Service shall constitute your acceptance of the Privacy Policy.

You may object to the processing by Finity of your personal data. However, in this case, Finity may not be in a position to provide the Paper.li Service.

You can exercise your right to object to the processing detailed in the Privacy Policy by contacting Finity at [legal@paper.li](mailto:legal@paper.li).

## Governing Law

By accessing the [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) Service, you and Finity agree that all matters relating to your access to, or use of, [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of Switzerland, without giving effect to any principles of conflicts of law.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this policy or the [Paper.li](https://paper.li/) service, please contact us at [legal@paper.li](mailto:legal@paper.li).
